

Contact

+855 (0) 86 72 33 27

has.sothea@itc.edu.kh

https://hassothea.github.io/

Phnom Penh, Cambodia

Education

Postdoctoral researcher

CNRS and ENS, Paris, France

Topic: Applied ML in Atmosphere

Topic: Applied ML in Atmospheric Science 2024

PhD in Applied Math

Sorbonne Unversité, Paris, France Topic: Theoretical & Applied ML 2022

Master M2MO

Université Paris Diderot, Paris, France Main focus: Financial Math & Data Science 2018

Engineer of Applied Math

ENSIIE, Evry, France

Main focus: Financial Math & Data Science

2018

Bachelor of Pure Math

Royal University of Phnom Penh, Cambodia Main focus: Pure mathematics 2014

Language

Khmer: mother tongue

English: fluent

French: conversational

SOTHEA HAS

PhD in Applied Mathematics

Summary

I am a senior lecturer researcher at the Department of Applied Math and Statistics (AMS) of ITC, Phnom Penh. I specialize in theoretical and applied machine learning (ML), statistics, stochastic modeling, and data science. My postdoctoral research focused on applying Transfer Learning Neural Networks for reconstructing balloon-observed gravity waves within atmospheric science. I can handle various types of data, and I am proficient in Python (including library development), PyTorch, R, C++, and MATLAB...

Experience

Postdoctoral researcher Sep 2022 - Present Laboratoire de Météorologie Dynamique - ENS

- Reconstructing balloon-observed gravity wave momentum fluxes using ML and inputs from ERA5.
- Extracting important features for the reconstruction.
- · Physical interpretation.
- Analyzing **SGD** algorithm using continuous-time **stochastic processes**.

PhD research

Aug 2018 - Aug 2022

LPSM - Sobronne Université

- Combine supervised and unsupervised methods for energy modeling.
- Consensual & high-dimensional aggregation methods.
- Build "gradientcobra" python library.

Teaching

UFR Mathématiques - Paris 7

Sep 2018 - Mar 2024

- Data Analysis with R and Rstudio.
- Data Mining with R and Rstudio.
- Exploratory Data Analysis with R and Rstudio.
- · Algorithm and Programming with Python.
- · Big Data Technologies with Python and Spark.
- · Statistical Inference and Data Modeling.

Institute of Technology of Cambodia Sep 2024 - Present

- Statistics (Year 3)
- Exploratory Data Analysis & Unsupervised Learning (Year 5)
- Advanced Machine Learning (Master 2)
- EDA & Unsupervised Learning (Master 1)

Publication

- Estimating balloon-observed gravity wave momentum fluxes using ML & input from ERA5. Published in JGR - Atmosphere, 2024.
- Gradient COBRA: A kernel-based consensual aggregation for regression. Published in Journal of Data Science, Statistics and Visualization, 2023.
- A consensual aggregation of randomly projected high-dimensional features of predictions. Available in HAL, 2022.
- Machine learning methods applied to the global modeling of event-driven pitch angle diffusion coefficients during high-speed streams. Published in Frontiers Physics, 2022.
- KFC: A clusterwise supervised learning procedure based on aggregation of distances.
 Published in Journal of Statistical Computation and Simulation, 2021.